Shoaib Ur Rehman Khan

Software Engineer



shoaiburrehman249@gmail.com



https://shoaiburrehman.github.io/



(+92) 3072522920



SB-52, Block13-B, Gulshan e Igbal, Karachi



Shoaib Ur Rehman Khan



github.com/shoaiburrehman

SKILLS

C++, C#, OOP & Data Structure Understanding.

Python and Flask Framework Knowledge.

Python Libraries (numpy, pandas, matplotlib, seaborn, tensorflow, sklearn models, statsmodel).

Data Collection, Data Cleaning, EDA, Data Visualization, Feature Engineering.

Model Building with Machine Learning and Deep Learning.

Developing Mobile Applications.

HTML, CSS & Bootstrap.

JS & its Libraries, i.e. React, React Native also with Hooks.

Relational DB like: MS SQL Server, Oracle, PostgreSQL, MySQL.

JIRA, GIT.

SOFTWARES

Spyder, Jupyter Notebook, MS Excel & Tableau Public.

VS Code, Android Studio.

Visual Studio, Adobe XD, LateX.

Familiar with Command Line Tool.

PROFILE

Software Engineer, graduated in 2019, trained in Mobile App Development. Motivated Software developer with around two years of Mobile App Development experience and passion for Data Science and its Python Libraries. Actively seeking opportunity to join a renowned organization for the betterment of my skills and knowledge and for the growth of the organization.

EXPERIENCE

Mobile Application Developer at e-Tools Software Pty. Ltd.

July 2021 – Till Present, Karachi

It is an Australian based Software Company. I work here in React-Native, my job is to develop and maintain their own product-based aged care Mobile Applications.

Junior Software Engineer at Vital Systems Pvt. Ltd.

November 2020 – July 2021, Karachi

Vital Systems is the project of Vital Groups, I worked here in React-Native, my job was to develop and maintain their own product-based mobile application Vital Cafe as per requirements with other side projects, i.e. Raaye which is already in Play Store & Vital POS Mobile Application.

Junior Software Developer at MITCO Software Company

October 2019 – November 2020, Karachi

Worked in React, React Native, Redux at MITCO where my job was to develop and maintain web and mobile application as per requirements in Linux platform.

Database Intern at TCS Logistics Company

SEPTEMBER 2018 - OCTOBER 2018, Karachi

Here I got the opportunity to be in Oracle Development team where they work on Oracle, Apex and their OMS.

EDUCATION

Bachelors

SEPTEMBER 2015 – 2019, KARACHI

Usman Institute of Technology | BS Software Engineering

Higher Secondary Certificate (HSC)

2013 - 2015, KARACHI

Govt. Dehli College | Pre-Engineering

PROJECTS

Data Science Tasks (reference github)

- Glassdoor Data Science job salary prediction from scratch (web scrapping to model building also deployed it using FlaskAPI).
- Car Price Prediction to Identify Pakistan used Car prices (EDA to model building, also deployed it using FlaskAPI.
- Time Series Analysis Task of Future Sales Prediction for next month from ARIMA Model and LSTM Approach.
- Object Detection, Sentiment Analysis and other tasks on my Portfolio Site.

CERTIFICATIONS

DeepLearning.Al TensorFlow Developer Professional Certificate

This is Coursera's 4 Courses deeplearning.ai Professional Certification (ref. linkedin)

IBM Data Science Professional Certificate

This is Coursera's 9 Courses IBM Professional Certification (ref: linkedin)

Artificial Intelligence Certification from PIAIC

This was the 4 Modules Certification started in 2019.